<!--
  ~ Copyright 2005-2007 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com)
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
       "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<body>
<p>WSO2 Carbon [<a href="docs_index.html"> Documentation Index </a>]</p>

<h1>
    Welcome to WSO2 Carbon
</h1>

<h2>Overview</h2>

<p>WSO2 Carbon is the award-winning base platform for WSO2's enterprise-grade middleware stack. It provides the core
    capabilities for security, clustering, logging, statistics, and management, and through a technology called OSGi, 
    higher level capabilities can be readily added as components to this core. The WSO2 Carbon core platform hosts a
    rich set of middleware components encompassing capabilities such as service hosting and management, message routing
    and transformation, governance and identity management, business process management and business activity
    monitoring, and more. The point-and-click WSO2 Carbon Component Manager makes it a snap to select the perfect set
    of components to address your unique requirements.</p>

<div style="border: 1px solid rgb(204, 204, 204); padding: 0px 20px; margin-left: 20px; margin-top: 10px;
                    margin-bottom: 10px; width: 280px; background-color: rgb(238, 238, 238);">
    <h3 style="margin-top: 10px;">Carbon-based Products</h3>
    <ul style="list-style-type: none; list-style-image: none; list-style-position: outside;
                    margin-left: 0px; padding-left: 0px;">
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/enterprise-service-bus/">
                <img alt="WSO2 ESB" src="./images/esb_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/web-services-application-server">
            <img alt="WSO2 Web Services Application Server" src="./images/wsas_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/data-services-server/">
            <img alt="WSO2 Data Services Server" src="./images/ds_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/governance-registry/">
            <img alt="WSO2 Governance Registry" src="./images/greg_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/identity-server/">
            <img alt="WSO2 Identity Solution" src="./images/identity_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/business-activity-monitor/">
            <img alt="WSO2 Business Activity Monitor" src="./images/bam_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/business-process-server/">
            <img alt="WSO2 Business Process Server" src="./images/bps_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/business-rules-server/">
            <img alt="WSO2 Business Rules Server" src="./images/brs_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/mashup-server/">
            <img alt="WSO2 Mashup Server" src="./images/mashup_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
        <li>
            <a href="http://wso2.com/products/gadget-server/">
            <img alt="WSO2 Gadget Server" src="./images/gs_logo_h23.gif"/>
            </a>
        </li>
    </ul>
</div>

<p/>
<h2>WSO2 Carbon Architecture</h2>

<p>WSO2 Carbon is based on Java OSGi technology which allows components to be dynamically installed, started, stopped,
    updated, and uninstalled, as well as eliminating component version conflicts. In Carbon, this capability translates
    into a solid core of common middleware components useful across any enterprise project, plus the ability to add
    components for specific features needed to solve a specific enterprise scenario. </p>

<div style="margin-left: 20px; margin-top: 10px;margin-bottom: 10px;">
    <a href="./images/wso2-carbon-architecture-small.png">
        <img alt="WSO2 Carbon Architecture" src="./images/wso2-carbon-architecture-small.png"/>
    </a>
</div>

<p>The core set of components in WSO2 Carbon provides WSO2 middleware products with a consistent set of enterprise-class
    management, security, clustering, logging, statistics, tracing, throttling, caching, and other capabilities as well
    as a management UI framework. Central to these components is WSO2’s solid and high performance SOA and Web Services
    engine. Add-in components encapsulate major types of functionality.</p>

<p>A unified graphical management console can deploy, manage, and view services, processes, process instances, and
    statistics across the whole platform, comprising of different products. As each runtime component is added,
    associated management components are added to the UI. With a clean front-end/back-end separation between the UI
    and the runtime, all capabilities can be controlled through a remote WSO2 Carbon UI, or through a clean Web Services
    interface.</p>

<div style="margin-left: 20px; margin-top: 10px;margin-bottom: 10px;">
<a href="./images/wso2-carbon-products-small.png">
    <img alt="WSO2 Carbon Based Products" src="./images/wso2-carbon-products-small.png"/>
</a>
</div>

<p>We use Carbon as the core of our middleware products, which are simply common “constellations” of components
    reflecting familiar middleware product categories. Most users will start with one of these categories, but rest
    easy in the assurance that components can be added to encompass requirements. </p>

</body>
</html>