<!--
  ~ Copyright 2005-2007 WSO2, Inc. (http://wso2.com)
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~ http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1//EN"
       "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml11/DTD/xhtml11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<body>
<p>WSO2 Carbon - User Guide [<a href="docs_index.html"> Documentation Index </a>]</p>

<h1>
    WSO2 Carbon User Guide
</h1>

<p>WSO2 Carbon user guide provides information on starting and configuring the product. And also it is a good starting place
    for users who are new to WSO2 Carbon.</p>

<h2 id="Installing">Installing and Running the WSO2 Carbon</h2>
<p>Please refer the <a href="installation_guide.html">Installation Guide</a>
      for details on how to install and run the WSO2 Carbon.</p>

<h2 id="Accessing">Accessing the WSO2 Carbon Web based Management Console</h2>

<p><a id="access">Once WSO2 Carbon has been successfully installed and started, launch a Web
      browser instance and point it to the URL </a><a class="externalLink" href="https://localhost:9443/carbon">https://localhost:9443/carbon</a>.
      This will take you to the <em>Sign In</em> page of the WSO2 Carbon</p>

<img src="images/carbon-login-page.png" alt="Sign-in" border="1"/>
<p>Figure: Sign-in Page</p>


<h2 id="Signing">Signing In</h2>
<p>Enter your user name and password to log on to the Carbon Management Console.</p>
<p><strong>The default username / password is : admin / admin</strong></p>

<p>You can change your password using the <a href="#Changing">instructions</a>
      given below.</p>
<p>If you get any errors when trying
      to sign in, click <strong>Sign-in Help</strong>. A list of
      possible errors, their descriptions and solutions will be displayed.</p>

<h2 id="Changing">Managing Users and Roles</h2>
<p>You can manage user and roles in the system by user management facility available in the web-based management console.
     Click on User Management menu from left.</p>

<p>Please refer the <a href="user/docs/userguide.html">documentation</a> on managing users for details.</p>

<h2 id="provisiong">Managing Features of WSO2 Carbon</h2>

<p>WSO2 Carbon comes with a facility called "Feature Manager" which provides GUI to help developers customize
    WSO2 Carbon and Carbon based products with ease. You can provision WSO2 Carbon with various feature available in
    feature repositories. The list of avaialbe repositoris are listed
    <a href="http://wso2.org/projects/carbon/provisioning-wso2-carbon-with-equinox-p2">here</a></p>

<p>For a comprehensive documentation on using the feature manager facility, please refer <a href="component-mgt/docs/userguide.html">this</a>. </p>
</body>
</html>  